Rumely, F.S. mss. II, 1841-1955 LMC 1893
Lilly Library
Rumely, F.S. mss. II
1841-1955
Lilly Library
Rumely, Fanny (Scott), 1877-1979
LMC 1893
1 Box 1 standard
The Rumely, F.S. mss. II, 1841-1955, are largely the personal and business papers of Fanny (Scott) Rumely, 1877- 1979, of LaPorte, Indiana.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Fanny (Scott) Rumely, 1877-1979, of LaPorte, Indiana was the daughter of Emmet Hoyt and Mary Relief (Niles) Scott. She graduated from LaPorte High School in 1895, attended Smith College and graduated from that institution in 1900, and returned to LaPorte where she became a teacher. In 1910, Fanny Scott married Edward Aloysius Rumely, also a LaPorte native and founder of Interlaken School where she was teaching. After marriage, Fanny had four children and managed the family farms while her husband was frequently away engaged in business and political reform.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Scope and Content Note
Included are the family Christmas letters and lists from 1932 to 1955. Early letters are those of diplomat Nathaniel Niles to John Barron Niles, March 1, 1941, and of E.A. Rumely to relatives during his school days in Germany in 1903-1904. Throughout the period of 1933-1945, there are references to the work of the Committee for the Nation by E.A. Rumely.
In addition to letters from members of the family, some of the correspondents are: Edward Chester Congdon, Eleanor M. Gillespie, H.M Hvid, David Curtis Stephenson, Fred H. Simons, Henry Luther Stoddard, Robert Elkington Wood.
Related Material
See Rumely, F.S. mss., Rumely mss., and Rumely mss. II, also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1981
Women; Rumely, Fanny (Scott), 1877-1979
- 1841-1929 (Box 1)
- 1930 (Box 1)
- 1931-1932 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1932 (Box 1)
- January-July 1933 (Box 1)
- August-December 1933 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1933 (Box 1)
- January-June 1934 (Box 1)
- July-December 1934 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1934 (Box 1)
- January-June 1935 (Box 1)
- July-December 1935 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1935 (Box 1)
- 1936 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1936 (Box 1)
- January-July 1937 (Box 1)
- August-December 1937 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1937 (Box 1)
- January-June 1938 (Box 1)
- July-December 1938 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1938 (Box 1)
- 1939 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1939 (Box 1)
- January-August 1940 (Box 1)
- September-December 1940 (Box 1)
- 1941 (Box 1)
- 1942-1943 (Box 1)
- 1944 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1944 (Box 1)
- 1945 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1945 (Box 1)
- 1946 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1946 (Box 1)
- 1947 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1947 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1948 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1949 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1950 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1951 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1952 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1953 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1954 (Box 1)
- Christmas letters and lists, 1955 (Box 1)
- Undated (Box 1)
- E. A. Rumely articles, 1970 (Box 1)